This is kind of a culmination of a lot of things that we've been doing so I know that it's been a long day
But I figured a bit of a challenge might be fun to get people trying out something where there's not like a base waiting for you
So what I've gone ahead and done is I've gone ahead and duplicated the new dish form and just made it the edit dish form
And so for the sake of
Demoing it we could do the routes and everything but for the sake of time. I just kind of want to show how it works
So to make sure everything works, so let's go ahead and make sure that
See we're going to go inside of the dish page
And so this time we're going to actually change show new form
Show new form actually is no longer correct as far as what it is really what show new form should be
Is a series of values and so for now
We're just going to leave it as a string though, but basically it should either be new or it should be empty or it should be edit
That's kind of what I'm thinking so actually what we can do though
We're here to type stuff out. So let's go ahead and do show we'll call it a show state
Show form state and this will be basically we'll have it empty
It can be new or it can be edit and so then we'll type that to show form state and
Then by default it will be an empty string so this is good
We have some things to break though, so let's go ahead and do some things
So hide form
Basically whenever we hide the form we want to go back to empty string. We don't need it to show anything
So that's taking care of and
Then here now if the new query is showing we don't want it to be true, right?
This is where touch will be helping us is saying what do we need it to be we need it to be new and
Then now that I actually know this I'm actually I'm gonna I'm just gonna jump the gun to and say that if we get an
Edit query on it
Then show new form
That value is going to be edit and so now that I think about it show new form as a whole is actually the wrong name
So we're gonna rename all show new form to just show form
And so I just did that with the multi select and so now that we have that let's see
But bump bump bump bump
Then we'll go through show form. Okay, so when we click on this
We are going to show form is going to be equal to new. That's what we're going to do that will let us actually toggle the new form
And then we'll scroll down. Okay, so we have here filter item. Okay, so now this is a little bit tricky
Because after all our edit form
Doesn't actually show up in this it actually lives in this card
So now we got to dive into this card and we got to think okay well
What we need to do is we need to actually emit an edit event. That's what we really need to do
So let's go ahead and define that show. We so we have another event that we're gonna emit and this will be
Update or edit dish
This is call what it is and it's not alphabetical so I'm swap that real quick and then we'll pass up the dish that we want to edit
It's basically what we do
So then with that we know that happens
So now we can go ahead and say let's see. I'm going to go ahead and similarly const edit dish will create a new function
And then this will emit what we'll see let's see command space or control space edit dish perfect props dot dish
That looks good and now we have our edit button here. So let's go ahead and add the click and when we click it
We're gonna run edit dish and that is actually everything we need
So once we have that we can jump back up to the page and the page now will actually be able to listen for this event
So we have the edit dish and so what we can do here is we want to do
Let's just name it edit dish again
I'm maybe edit dish form that is a little bit cleaner
So then here now we can do
To
Neat here makes most sense edit dish form and we have a payload which is of type dish
And so now what we're going to do though is we're going to say show
Form
That values going to be edit and the reason this is valuable is because
We need now to actually toggle that component that we just grabbed the edit dish form
So again, there's going to be some repetition in here and I I know that that's always a little bit tricky
Manage sometimes especially if
See
We're used to that do not repeat yourself
context but
It is helpful sometimes just to focus on getting something out the door first rather than sort of optimizing for it
So this is the else if
So you can see here now I've updated the logic so that basically if show form is new show the new for dish form
Otherwise if the show form is edit
Show the edit dish form and then otherwise we will show the thing and so the key thing here though is
We're going to need to actually pass this into this
Component so to make sure this works. Oh silly me. This is wrong. This needs at least I'll just strict equal that
Okay, so to prove that this works, I'm going to go ahead and just say edit name right here
And then we'll go ahead and check to make sure everything worked
So
Where's my app? Oh, I think I closed it. Okay, we bump this up
Okay, we have our dishes
We're missing semi-colon
Dishes page. Let's find out
Dishes page I guess that was that error that we saw earlier
else oh silly me else if
There we go. That's good now. All right, so now there we go
All right, so we have the restaurants we have the dishes and now if we click on edit
Okay, so edit name is appearing we have the right component coming in so now what we need to do is we actually need to fetch the ID
So how are we going to do that? Well, what we can do is you can probably just for now let's see
How are we checking this instead of this page currently we have a show form dish list
Okay, so we know for a fact that edit dish is going to tell us the ID that's really what we ultimately need
So what I'm going to do is we're just going to create a ref that we're going to track for now
Called edit dish ID and this is going to be a ref that's just a string
And what we're going to want to do then is on the point of edit we will do edit dish ID
Value equals payload dot ID and we know that it happens because we know that dish itself has an ID property
So again once again typing to the rescue for this
Once we have this what this tells us is
Inside of edit is form we can have a prop that takes in that specific ID right so I can say define props
And then inside of the fine props we'll take a
I don't want to call it ID because it'll conflict with HTML specs
That's usually a rule. I try to establish whenever I write anything so we'll just call it dish ID and
This will be basically a string
We don't need to be anymore complicated than that
So now that we've defined the props here we should be able to inside of our
Edit dish component
There we go we can then say dish ID is going to be equal to edit dish ID just like that
And then I realize it's not always going to be true. We won't always have one so inside of our edit dish
We're going to just make it optional
So that doesn't yell at us
Okay, that should do the trick and then to make sure this works
We'll go ahead and render out the edit or dish ID. I think it's what I call it. Yeah, dish ID. That's what I call it
Okay, let's see this works at all. So if I click edit
Refresh edit there we go there's our ID
If we go back
I didn't I I didn't turn away the cancel it. That's a totally fine. Okay, so now that we have our ID what do we need to do?
Okay, we need to actually get the thing from the store and the way we're going to do that
Is inside of stores something you might not be aware of is that getters can actually receive an argument
So we can basically pass in an argument to get to basically do a little bit of fetching
So in this case we will say get so in this case it would be get dish
by ID
And so we know that we get the state by default right from our woo that's wrong. There you go
And then what we're going to return though is we're going to return a dish that's something to that's important
So what we're going to do is we're going to return
the state dot
the
list.filter and
We're going to filter what we're going to filter every dish inside of here and dish.id should be oh
Sorry, we need a function first of this new edit dish ID
So basically what we're doing is inside of the getter is a function returning a function and that's why we can pass in a parameter
So the edit dish ID will return
This filter dish and there should be enter in like this and then that should clean up the errors although it's slightly off
Edit dish ID string
Why is it not happy with this?
So this is where it's an example of like unfortunately sometimes the errors aren't as helpful
But we kind of got ahead of ourselves thinking oh well we'll get dish by ID not quite
The thing that's getting the dish is actually the function and all we're actually returning is the function in this case
Okay, let's now try this
So if we go inside of our edit dish form we should be able to then say
Cons edit
Target dish is equal to
We have this story yet. I don't have this story yet. Cons dish store
Because use this store and
Then because I dish store dot get dish by ID and then we need the props here
So we say props that dish ID and then we can log target dish
Do do do do but I think it's yelling at me because it's saying hey
It might not be
And it might not it might be undefined
So I'll just do this it props
That dish ID is true
Then do that
Yes, this is gonna be a little bit weird
This is weird type wise already, but I want to see this works. So here we go
So we have our console here
We have our ghost peppers
Okay, so we can see here now we've actually fetch the actual object
So all we got to do now here is
Inside of here once again we have an area to do
Fix types
But once again, we're trying to get to the finish line here
So now that we actually have the dish
What we want to be able to do is actually update it so in this particular case what I would say is
How do we do this so we have edit name
This name v model dish.name okay
So what I actually could do instead is we can just say the value is new dish.name
That's fine, but then on input
We will then say or on key up that enter just like we did before
Then we'll say update dish
So the way we'll do that is cons update dish is
Going to go ahead and it's just a normal function and then we're going to say target dish.name equals new dish dot value dot name
Can I do that?
Yeah, that's fine. I'll fix the types in a second. We just want to see this works. Okay
Swap it on over so then we'll say mystery shrimp create
Oh wait that one actually oh that should that should trigger it so now if I go back to dishes
All it broke
Okay edit
Test create
dishes
Nope
Does not like it update dish
Oh, I didn't hit enter silly me
Okay, that should do it now
So then we'll refresh
Edit here mystery shrimp enter
Enter did something and then if I go back to dishes
I want to go back oh I know why silly me
Because I haven't actually so I thought I was doing routing this is this requires an actual switch
So similarly we need to cancel an edit dish basically and I realized on the edit dish form for whatever reason
Yeah, okay, this is what I need to switch so going back to the dishes page
We'll go back to the dish card and so when we cancel
Yeah, wait, wait, here we go
Listen to cancel dish cancel new dish then we'll say cancel
dish or cancel edit
And so now we can do constant cancel edit
Equals a function where we then say the show form dot value equals that so basically we're
Reverting it back to the thing so the show that works will go ahead and edit
We'll click cancel and it did not like it cancel
Cannot admit that the
I
did not get declared okay, so this is where views trying to help us because I made up an event without actually declaring it
So cancel edit dish like this that should do it
Okay, so refresh again goes peppers
Mystery oh actually cancel first
It does not like it
What is not picking up?
I think it says cancel new dish on the template
Oh, is that what it's saying on the template?
Yes, I think you're right so be scroll down here. Yeah
Wait nope wrong thing cancel edit dish
Typing is fun
Let's do this all right refresh edit cancel there we go now. We're good. So now mystery shrimp
Enter that should update it
It just overrided it but okay, but that's the general gist of it right there's kind of a lot of moving pieces here
And so what I will make sure to do is that I'll make sure that the end result is updated because there's clearly a lot of moving pieces
But a high level what we did see is that you basically need to be able to hop into the store
Use getters to grab something out and then what's tricky and most likely what's happening at this point is that
You basically need to make a copy of the reference before you go off and modify it. I was trying to take a shortcut here to just edit it directly
But typically what you do want to do is you want to actually mod it like basically when you load it in
Make a copy of it that way you have a local state change within your component of what you're modifying and then when you submit the change
That would trigger an update event to the store that will then update the set item. That's the path you want to follow
So once again that that solution will be published to the 11 finished branch
But otherwise this is also a chance for you to just try and debug this out because this is honestly fairly common scenario too
As far as you know, credit operations and updating forms and existing data